Deepak Patel

Phone: +919582516686

Address: 49-C

Pocket-3, Mayur Vihar Phase-1,

New Delhi - 110091

Email: deepakpatel.1991@gmail.com

Articulate reporter adept in all aspects of researching, writing and producing engaging news stories. Having worked in two prominent newspapers and one news agency in the country, I am aware of the challenges of the job and the skill set required in delivering credible work. I believe that broadening my job portfolio at this stage would help me learn to catch the nerve of news faster and better.

EXPERIENCE

Business Standard July 2014 -- July 2016

Correspondent

- Wrote stories for multiple platforms, including internet and print channels.
- Reported on key sectors such as business law, corporate affairs, pharmaceuticals, steel and mines.
- Covered government/ministry policy affairs in the specified beats.
- Wrote in-depth analytical and feature stories
- Work history: http://www.business-standard.com/author/search/keyword/deepak-patel

The Indian Express

August 2016 -- December 2018

Principal Correspondent

- Reported on key sectors such as coal, power, mines, pharmaceuticals and commerce.
- Covered government/ ministry policy affairs and corporate sectors in the specified beats.
- Regularly wrote in-depth analytical stories as well as investigative stories.
- Work history: http://indianexpress.com/profile/author/deepak-patel/

Press Trust of India (PTI)

December 2018 to present

Chief Correspondent

- Reported on key sectors such as civil aviation and pharmaceuticals.
- Reporting partially on national politics.
- Covered public policy and corporate sector in the specified beats.
- Extensively covered the routine events in specified beats and gathered valuable experience in filing news articles quickly.

EDUCATION

Indian Institute of Mass Communication

July 2013-May 2014

Post Graduate Diploma in English Journalism

Dharmsinh Desai University

July 2008-May 2013

Bachelor of Engineering

SKILLS

- Investigative skills
- Team player
- Good at number crunching
- Strictly adhere to deadlines and adept at handling work pressure
- Sound editorial judgment

LANGUAGES

English, Hindi, Gujarati